Capital Area Council of Churches; Records apap129
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Subject Files, 1953-1989; 4; 3.6 cubic ft.
  - Christians United in Mission, Inc., 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Church Women United, 1985-1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Civil Defense Clergy, 1953-1955 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Clergy-Physicians Dinner, 1955-1959 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Clergy-Physicians Dinner, 1962-1963 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Clinical Pastoral Training, 1960-1961 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Community Groups, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Community Thanksgiving Day Service, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Community Worship, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Community Worship, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Community Worship Committee, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Council of Churches Agency, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Crop Cooperative, 1987 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Crop Walk, Recruiting, 1984-1986 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Crop Walk, 1985-1987 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Crop Walk, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Department of Christian Education, Rev. James Richard, 1958-1961 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Department of Christian Education, Roy Damonte Chair, 1961-1962 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Department of Christian Living, 1957 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Department of Christian Living, 1959-1961 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Department of Hospitality Ministry, 1961 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Department of Hospitality Ministry, 1961-1964 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Ecumenical Event, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Ecumenical Relations, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Eden Park Nursing Home, 1987-1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - ELCA Hudson Mohawk Conference, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Energy, Nuclear, etc., 1978 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Equinox, 1988 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Faith and Learning Commission, 1989 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Faith and Order, 1962-1963 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Faith and Order Department, Thomas Hunter, Chair, 1964-1965 (Box 1 (4-Subject Files), Folder 49-50)
  - Family Life, Undated (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Family Planning, 1988-1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Films, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Food Pantries for Capital District, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Gambling, 1979 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Giles, Joyce S. Installation, 1977 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Good Friday, 1982, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Habitat for Humanity, 1988-1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - HANNYS, Hunger Action Network of New York State, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Holocaust Services, 1986 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Holy Week, 1957 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Holy Week, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Homeless, 1988-1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Homeless Shelters, 1987 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Horizon House, Minutes, By-laws, Financial Reports, and Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Horizon House, Minutes, By-laws, Financial Reports, and Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Horizon House, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Horizon House and Seamans Agency History, 1978-1981 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Hospital Chaplains, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Hospitality Ministry, Clergy Physicians Dinner, 1969 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Hospital Work (AMCH) [Albany Medical Center Hospital], 1986 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Housing, 1988-1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Hunger Issues, 1985-1986 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Impact, 1988-1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Inclusive Language Resources, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Inner-City Prior to 1967, 1966 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Intensive English Program, 1990 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Interdenominational Ministers Association, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Interfaith Community of Schenectady, 1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Interfaith Experiences, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Interfaith Partnership for the Homeless, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Interfaith Partnership for the Homeless, 1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Interfaith Social Action Coalition, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - International Club, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Installation Service/Assembly, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Institute for Christian Living, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Institute for Christian Living, 1962-1963 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Institute for Christian Living, Peter Libassi, Chair, 1959 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 38)
  - Institute for Christian Living, Robert Hudnut, Chair, 1959-1960 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 39)
  - Institute for Christian Living, Robert Hudnut, Chair, 1961-1962 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 40)
  - Institutional Ministries, 1981-1985 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 41)
  - Institutional Ministries, 1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 42)
  - Jail Ministry, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 43)
  - Jail Ministry and Phase Out/Re-Entry (PORE), 1980-1981 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 44)
  - Jail Ministry and Phase Out/Re-Entry, 1981-1982 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 45)
  - Jail Ministry, 1982-1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 46)
  - Jail Ministry, 1984-1987 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 47)
  - Jail Ministry, 1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 48)
  - Job Fair, 1987 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 49)
  - Junior League, 1987-1988 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 50)
  - Knickerbocker Lenten Meditations, 1955 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 51)
  - Labor Religion Coalition, 1987 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 52)
  - Labor Religion Coalition, 1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 53)
  - Leadership Training School, 1958 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 54)
  - Leadership Training School, 1959 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 55)
  - Leadership Training School, Rev. Robert Withers, 1960 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 56)
  - Legislation, 1981-1984 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 57)
  - Literacy Volunteers of America, 1989 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 58)
  - Luncheon Forums, 1986-1987 (Box 2 (4-Subject Files), Folder 59)
  - Martin Luther King, Miscellaneous, 1984-1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Martin Luther King Services, 1985-1987 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Martin Luther King Scholarship, 1989-1990 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Mental Health, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Mental Health, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures, 1940-1976 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Mohawk Hudson Foundation, 1985 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Mohawk Hudson Foundation, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Music Festivals, 1957-1964 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Musical, 1984-1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Musical Celebrations, 1980-1981 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Musical Celebration, 1986 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Musical Celebration, 1987 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Musical Celebration, 1988-1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Muslim Christian Relations, Office of, Newsletter, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Albany Branch, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - New Clergy, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - New York Council of Churches, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - News Clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - New York State Council of Churches, 1988-1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Niebuhr Institute Planning Committee, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Nominations for the Corlyle Adams Ecumenical Award-Form for, Undated (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Organ Donor Workshop, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Peace and Justice, 1985-1986 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Peace and Justice, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Peace and Justice, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - People Resources, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 28-29)
  - Prayer and Worship Commission, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Prayer Walk, 1987 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Prayer Walk, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Professor Albright Luncheon, 1958 January 7 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Quilt Tricentennial, 1986 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Research and Planning, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Retreat Centers, 1988 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Retreat Centers, 1989 (Box 3 (4-Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Schenectady Inner City Ministry, 1989 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, News Clippings, 1963-1969 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - Senior Citizens, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - Senior Housing, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Senior Service Center/ Board, 1988-1989 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Sexual Violence, 1989 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Singles Outreach Support, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Social Action Coalition, 1989 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Social Education and Action, John W. Jennings, Chair, 1963-1964 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Social Justice Center, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Somaltow Housing Co. Inc., 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Somaltow Housing Co. Inc., South Mall Towers, 1989 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Song Sheets, Undated (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - South End Ecumenical Community, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - South Mall Towers, 1986-1987 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Spirituality, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Substance Abuse, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Substance Abuse, 1989 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Task Force on Advocacy for the Spanish Speaking, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Teresian House, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Texas Faith Friends, 1988 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Thanksgiving Worship, 1985-1986 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Training Seminar for Program for Peace, 1959-1960 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Tricentennial, 1986 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Tri-Cities Mass Communications Committee, George Hosler, Chair, 1961-1962 (Box 4 (4-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - UNICEF, 1987 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - United Nations, 1988 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - United Nations, 1989 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - University Heights, 1988 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Upstate New York Synod ELCA, 1988 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Vacation Church School Institute, 1957 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Vacation Church School Institute, 1958 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Vision Interfaith Satellite Network, Communications, 1988 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Vision Interfaith Satellite Network, Communications, 1988-1989 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Women in Ministry, 1984-1988 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Youth, 1989 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Youth Council, Constitution, 1954-1960 (Box 5 (4-Subject Files), Folder 12)
- Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987, 5; 2 cubic ft.
  Series 5 includes minutes of the three formative meetings held in 1941 as well as the official documentation of incorporation and topical correspondence. Included in the minutes, or as supplements filed with them, are lists of member churches, size of congregations, financial contributions and indications of existing organizations particular to a single denomination. The names of member congregation's representatives and Council officers are also included with consistency.
  Included is one folder of older meeting minutes (Box 1, Folder 1: 1940, 1942-45) from the Albany City Council of Religious Education, which later came under the auspices of the CACC and Hospital Ministry minutes (Box 2, Folder 18: 1954-61). The remainder of the series are minutes from the monthly meetings of the executive committee and/or board of directors of the Federation/Council. Correspondence is often filed along with the minutes of the meeting at which the letter was discussed. Typically the minutes include a list of attendees; the leader of the opening prayer; the approval of the minutes of the previous meting; report from the president, executive director, treasurer and committee chairs; record of any resolutions or topics of discussion; announcements and a statement of adjournment.
  - Albany City Council of Religious Education, Executive Committee, 1940, 1942-1945 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 1)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1941-1944 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 2)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1945-1948 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 3)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1948 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 4)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1949 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 5)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1950 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 6)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1951 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 7)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1952 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 8)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1953 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 9)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1954 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 10)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1955 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 11)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1956 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 12)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1957 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 13)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1958 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 14)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1959 (Box 1 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors, 1960 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, 1961 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, 1962 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, 1963-1966 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, 1967-1969 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, 1970-1976 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, 1977-1978 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, 1981 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors, 1982 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors, 1983 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors, 1984 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors, 1985 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors, 1987 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors, 1988 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 17)
  - Hospital Ministry, Minutes and Meetings, 1954-1961 (Box 2 (5-Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987), Folder 18)